这就是性侵给人留下的印记
That's what abuse does to you, you know?
它把我变成了 一块吸引生活中各种怪胎的磁石
It made me this sticking plaster for all of life's weirdos.
一个血淋淋的伤口 任他们嗅闻
This... open wound for them to sniff at.
我知道她是个疯子 我知道她很危险
I knew she was mad, and I knew she was dangerous,
但她夸赞了我 那就足够了
but she flattered me. That was enough.
一个观众偷偷录下了我的自白
A random audience member recorded me on the sly
然后发到了油管上 那个视频一下子就火了
and uploaded the video to YouTube, and it went viral.
不出几周
In a matter of weeks,
我就从一个透明的边缘人 变成了热点人物
I went from a walking ghost to the center of a media storm.
我感到不知所措 因而几乎没注意到
It was so overwhelming that I almost didn't notice
玛莎停止了对我的邮件轰炸
that Martha had stopped emailing.
新的工作机会不断涌现 令我应接不暇
Too distracted by all the new work opportunities to take notice.
就像被什么东西附身了一样 一股脑全说了出来
It was like something took over, and I just started coming out with it.
播客、广播节目 更大型的演出 更多的观众
Podcasts, radio shows, bigger gigs, better crowds.
所有人都想见我
Everyone wanted a piece of me,
一时之间 我的事业开始扶摇直上
and my career sprung into surprising action.
一切都好像在做梦一样
I honestly couldn't believe it was all happening.
有生以来第一次 我真正感觉自己正在迈向成功
For the first time in my life, I really felt like I was going somewhere.
女士们先生们 让我们热情欢迎他登场
Ladies and gentlemen, please welcome to the stage
唐尼·邓恩
Donny Dunn!
如今我的生活肉眼可见地蒸蒸日上
And there is nothing like your life going so visibly well
这就是对性侵者最好的回击
to let your sexual abuser know,
"去你的 你毁不了我"
"Fuck you. You failed to break me."
非常感谢大家
Ah, thank you very much.
首先 我想对 看过那段视频的朋友们说
Now, for those of you that have seen the viral video,
别担心 我不会再那样发神经了
don't worry, I'm not gonna go into all that again.
然而前排有一个人 正用奇怪的眼神看着我
Although there is a guy in the front row looking at me a bit funny.
能查询一下 这家伙有没有犯罪记录吗?
Is it possible to get a DBS check on this guy, please?
一时间发生了太多的事 我完全跟不上节奏
I couldn't keep up with it, everything that was happening.
似乎过往三十年的人生中
It was like my life began three decades in,
我苦苦追寻的成功 只需要诚实面对自己就能实现
and all I needed to do to achieve it was to be honest with myself.
我竟歪打正着地找到了出路
It's funny how things work out.
有时我会忽然情绪失落
And sometimes I would find myself in the free fall of happiness,
问自己为何把一切憋在心里那么久
and wonder what it was in me that kept it in for so long.
我以往究竟在害怕些什么
What it was in me that felt so afraid.
你好
Hello.
我原本不想再跟你说话的
I wasn't gonna speak to you again,
但这段时间 我给你在台上说的话做了摘要
but I've been putting down the basics regarding what you said on stage.
你在视频里说的那些事 你爸妈知道吗?
Do your parents know about all that in the video, yeah?
那个男人掀开你的衣服 强奸你的事
The shirtlifting, and the guy's cock half hanging out of you.
我应该告诉他们吗?
I mean, should I tell them?
他们有权知道自己的儿子 是个丑陋的小基佬
Probably fair to know their son's an ugly little bumboy.
你说了那么多我的坏话 这点惩罚算轻的了
It's the least you deserve for all those things you said about me.
对于你的欺骗和伤害 我的愤怒根本无以言表
I cannot express how furious I am about the way you shafted me.
就这样 在最糟糕的时机
And just like that, at the worst possible time,
在我职业生涯中最重要的时刻
during the most important moment of my professional life,
玛莎得知了我的手机号码
Martha got my number.
我怎么会让她知道了我的手机号码?
How the fuck could I let her get my number?
驯鹿宝贝 你以为已经摆脱偶了?
从我的iPhone发送
《驯鹿宝贝》
第一条新消息
First new message.
我这段时间没有联系你父母
You know, I've been leaving your parents alone
是因为顾不上
because I didn't have the time for it,
但我觉得那种事情 他们会有兴趣知道的
but I think they're gonna wanna know information like this.
我不认为你爸是那种开明的类型
I don't think your dad looks like the accepting type.
我不知道玛莎是在吓唬我
I couldn't tell if Martha was bluffing,
还是真的会做出 向我家人告密那么恶劣的事
or if she would actually do something as awful as tell my family.
不管怎样 我好几天没理会她 专心思考应对之策
Either way, I unplugged from her for a few days and made plans.
我必须赶在她前面向我父母坦白
I just had to get to my parents before she did.
那个 我...
Look, I, um...
不知道你们有没有看过...
I don't know whether you've... seen this...
网上流传的一段我的视频
video of me that's been going around online.
没有 熊宝 我已经不用社交媒体了 而你爸爸...
No, bear, I'm not on social media anymore, and your dad--
不是个白痴
Isn't a fucking moron.
好吧 感谢你的评论
Okay. Thanks for that. Um...
是这样的
Well...
网上有一段视频
it's this video where I, uh...
我在里面坦白了很多事
I confess a lot of things.
我只是...
I just...
我感到很困惑
I just... I feel very confused,
而且 我...
and, um, I...
其实我也不知道该怎么办才好 但我想努力地
I don't really know anything anymore, but I'm trying to, you know, like,
渡过这个难关
get through it.
我发现我好像不是一个直男
I don't think I'm... I'm straight anymore. Um...
我想我有可能是
I think I'm probably, like,
双性恋
bisexual maybe.
无论如何 这段旅程 它...
It's a journey, anyway, but it's...
我需要你们的支持才能走下去
it's one that I... I need to go on with your support.
过去这几年真的很难熬
These past few years have been really difficult.
现在到你们做选择的时候了
And I think you're gonna have a choice now
你们的儿子可能是双性恋或者同性恋 无论结果如何 你们是愿意接纳我
between a... between a bi son or a... or a gay son, whatever I become,
还是恨不得我干脆自行了断 因为我真的受不了
or a dead one, because I can't handle it anymore.
再把这一切埋在心里了
Keeping it in.
亲爱的 事情很简单呀
Oh, love, that's easy.
面对这样的选择 我们的答案是毫无疑问的
Giving us a choice like that, there's no question which one we're gonna go for.
拜托 让我说完
Just... Please, just let me finish.
我在那段视频里 还提到了其他事情
And I sort of speak about... other things in the video too.
我被...
I was, um...
我曾经
I was
被一个男人强奸过
raped by a man.
天啊
Oh my God.
我没事 好吗? 我保证
I'm fine, all right? I promise.
但我在网上那段视频里 提到了这件事 现在所有人都知道了
But I spoke about it in this online video, and now everyone knows.
我觉得好丢脸
I just feel so fucking embarrassed,
之所以一直瞒着你们
and I guess I never wanted you to know
大概就是怕你们会觉得我...
because I didn't want you to think less of me,
就是
you know...
...不像个男人吧
...as a man.
亲爱的 我们怎么会那么想呢?
Oh, darling, of course we don't.
不管发生了任何事 你都是我们的儿子呀
You're our son, whatever happens.
我自己都感觉我不像个男人
I just feel less of one,
居然任由那种事发生在我身上
having let something like that happen to me.
但那种事你也不想的 这不能怪你
But you didn't let it happen. You weren't to blame.
你会觉得我不像个男人吗?
Would you see me as less of one?
什么?
What?
你会觉得我不像个男人吗?
Would you see me as less of a man?
呃 不会
Uh, well, no.
我是在天主教会的环境下长大的
I grew up in the Catholic Church.
抱歉 我...
Uh, sorry, I... I...
我不明白
I don't understand.
天啊 我...
Jesus. I...
我不知道该说什么了
I don't know what to say.
你什么都不用说
You don't have to say anything.
只要知道我们会永远支持你就好
Just know we are always here.
熊宝 我真心疼你
Oh, Bear, I'm so sorry.
那晚我足足睡了12个小时 睡醒后 迎来了一个崭新的黎明
I slept 12 hours that night and woke up to a new dawn.
我有种如释重负的感觉
I felt lighter somehow.
甚至有些惊讶于 忽然就找到了内心的平静
Amazed, even, by the sudden peace I found within myself.
接下来的几天我都待在苏格兰 手机关机 享受平静的生活
I spent the next few days in Scotland with my phone off, enjoying the quiet.
我把发生的一切都告诉了爸妈 泰瑞 玛莎 达瑞安
I told my parents everything. Teri, Martha, Darrien.
我这辈子从未如此自在过
I hadn't felt so at ease in all my life.
我再也不用害怕了
There was no need to be afraid anymore.
从来都不需要害怕
There was never any need.
踏上返回伦敦的列车那一刻
And by the time I boarded the train back down,
我真的感觉前路是一片坦途
I really felt like there was nothing in my way.
再没有任何阻碍 当然了 玛莎除外
Nothing, of course, apart from Martha.
祝你和变性人早日复合
Good luck with the transsexual.
好 谢谢你 老爸 只是...谢谢
Yep, thank you, Dad. Just... Thanks.
你们快回去吧
You can go now.
您有新的语音信息 来自未知号码
天啊
Jesus Christ.
欢迎使用语音信箱
Welcome to your voicemail.
您有50条新的消息
You have 50 new messages.
第一条新消息
First new message.
你像个白痴一样站在那里
You stood there, like a fucking guppy,
在我眼皮子底下聊起那个贱人
wafting that bitch right under my nose,
当众炫耀跟她的奸情
your cock practically in her,
你还指望我怎么样?
and you're expecting me to do what?
她此时此刻还在给我打电话 哪怕我人都在警局了
She's ringing me now, literally, as I stand here.
- 我看见了 邓恩先生 - 那快做点什么啊
- I can see that, Mr. Dunn. - Then do something.
一天之内给人打这么多电话 肯定是违法的吧
You can't ring somebody that many times in a day, surely.
确实 但因为来电的是未知号码
Well, no, you can't, but obviously with unknown numbers,
所以很难证明打电话的是同一个人
it's very difficult to prove who is actually calling.
你的意思是说 我可以给见过的 任何人打电话 打多少次都行
So you're saying I can call anyone I meet as many times as I want,
只要我隐藏自己的号码 就可以为所欲为了?
and as long as I withhold my number, I'm free to do as I please?
你不会真想这么干吧?
You're not planning to?
当然不会
No, I'm not planning to.
我只是在表达一个观点 这种行为应当被制止
I'm making a point. This behavior shouldn't be allowed.
她怎么会知道你的号码?
How'd she get your number anyway?
她之前停止了邮件骚扰 所以我就在邮箱设置了
She'd stopped emailing, so I set an out-of-office,
自动回复... 她肯定是从回复里看到的
and it must have... replied to her.
那你想必很难受吧
That's gotta hurt.
辛辛苦苦藏了这么久的电话号码 这么轻易就泄露了
Giving it away so easily after managing to keep it from her for so long.
你现在说这个有用吗?
Why is that helpful?
那...
Wha-- Uh...
你有试过屏蔽她的电话号码吗?
What about her phone number? Have you tried blocking that?
当然试过了 但陌生号码没法屏蔽
Of course I've tried. You can't block unknown numbers.
这你应该知道的
You should know this.
你就不能去后面 听听她留下的语音信息吗?
Can't you just go into the back and listen to the voicemails she's been leaving?
我们资源有限 听不了那么多语音留言
We can't listen to that many voicemails. We don't have the resources.
天哪 那现在是怎样? 我换个电话号码 向她认输?
Oh my God. So, what? I just change my number and let her win again?
其实 还有一个办法
Well, there is another option.
听着 这是我私下给你的建议
Now, I need to speak off the record here, but
你可以保留现在的号码
it might make sense to keep your number
等她说出某些过激言论 警方就能以之为依据加快调查
and wait for her to say something that we can use to expedite this case.
你是认真的吗?
You're serious?
只是一个建议
Merely a suggestion.
回家去吧 把她出言威胁的时刻统统记录下来
Go home. Mark down moments where she says something threatening.
她每天给你留那么多语音信息
She's leaving you numerous voicemails a day.
里面很可能存在 可以作为查案依据的内容
Chances are there'll be something there we can use.
第一条新消息 我实话跟你说了吧...
First new message. I'm gonna be frank with you...
接下来的几个月
Over the next few months,
玛莎的语音信息 成了我每日必听的播客
Martha's voicemails became the podcast to my life.
每次搭乘公交和地铁 走在街上赶去与人会面时
I listened to her on every bus ride, every Tube journey,
我都在听她的留言
in the street between meetings.
她的声音时刻萦绕在我耳边
She was there in my ears all the time.
别忘了我也说过要保密
Don't forget what I said about confidentiality.
在那些留言里 她不断追忆往昔
Her voicemails playing out this retrospective
细数着我们相处的点点滴滴
of our entire relationship together.
你说会满足我的需求时
When you said about hanging the curtains,
我以为你想玩一夜情
I assumed you had a one-night stand in mind.
桩桩件件 她都记得一清二楚
She remembered everything with such lucidity.
还记得你的那次演出吗? 就是在...
Do you remember that gig you performed at back in the day?
所有闲聊 谈笑
The chats, the laughter.
以及虚假的承诺
The false promises.
我很震惊 你居然会做出那种事
I'm shocked you did something like that.
简直匪夷所思 她居然会对种种情境
I couldn't believe the meaning she would glean
做出如此不切实际的解读
from the most implausible of places.
那天你为我沦陷了 不是吗? 在运河边那天
You surrendered to me that day, didn't you? By the water.
我开始下载那些语音 将它们进行记录和分类
I started to download them, log and categorize them,
用颜色做标记 按不同的情绪和主题归类
color-code them into different emotions and subjects.
你现在的名气毫无意义 那些人根本不爱你
All this fame means fuck all. They don't love you.
他们总有一天会厌倦的 但我爱你 知道吗?
They'll grow bored. I love you. Yeah?
我开始沉迷其中
It became an obsession.
无视工作方面的来电 取消演出和访谈
I ignored work calls, canceled gigs and interviews,
把时间和精力 都投入在解读玛莎这个谜团
devoted my life to unpacking the mystery of Martha.
她为什么会变成现在这样
Why she was the way that she was.
我不知道自己可曾接近过答案
I'm not sure I ever got close to finding the answer.
你有心理问题 宝贝
You've got psychiatric problems, darling.
事实上 渐渐地 我发现自己又开始与她产生共鸣了
In fact, over time, I found myself relating to her all over again.
我们同样缺乏安全感 对未来感到恐惧
Our shared insecurities, our fears for the future.
夜晚会因同样的烦恼难以入眠
The same things at night which kept us from our sleep.
伦敦有太多喜欢冒充内行 背后捅刀子和刻意欺骗的人了
London's full of charlatans and backstabbers and liars.
她能转移我的注意力 让我不去想自己失去的一切
The way she managed to distract me from all the things that I'd lost.
她威胁过我很多次
She threatened me many times,
说过很多凶残可怕的话
said stuff that was violent or phobic.
性侵这种事不该是 小男孩和钢琴老师之间的剧情吗?
Isn't abuse for little boys and their piano teachers?
关于我 泰瑞和性侵的都有
About me or Teri or the abuse.
但我仍然选择了无视...
But still, I found myself ignoring it.
最近有什么 需要通报警方的新进展吗?
Has anything new come up that we should know about?
没有
No.
...也许是着了魔 也许是出于空虚 或者内疚 我没有举报她
Holding off reporting her out of fascination or empathy or guilt.
其实那些都是 我不想摆脱她的借口罢了
Any excuse to keep her in my life.
你敢
Don't you dare!
有时候 在人生的至暗时刻
And sometimes, in my darkest hours,
我躺在床上彻夜不眠 听着她叙述自己的挣扎...
as I lay awake, listening to how much she was suffering...
每到夜晚 我的心情都很沉重 有时我会无比愤怒
I get heavy at night. I sometimes feel so angry.
气这个世界对我放肆地掠夺
Angry at the world and what it's taken from me.
...我得拼尽全身的力气 才能阻止自己回拨给她
I did have to fight every fiber of my being not to call her back.
所以当我最终决定举报她时
So when I did eventually report her,
仅仅是因为她开始对我家人下手了
I only did it because she started on my family.
仅仅是因为 我感觉无法再承担之后的风险了
I only did it because it felt like a risk I couldn't take any longer.
新消息
Message.
你和你的家人都装聋作哑 是吧?
So you and your family, you keep your traps shut, yeah?
最后一次警告你 我他妈是认真的
You're on your final warning. I fucking mean it this time.
因为我患上了严重的经前紧张综合征
Because I've got a raging PMT
有可能拿刀去捅全英国的任何人
where I could just about stab anyone in England, in Britain.
所以你讲话最好小心点 因为没准我哪天就会去捅人
So you'd better watch what you're saying because maybe one day I will stab someone.
玛莎第二天就被捕了
Martha was arrested the next day
被控三项跟踪和骚扰罪名
and charged with three counts of stalking and harassment.
直到她的认罪听证会日期确定下来
And by the time a date was set for her plea hearing,
我都无法分辨这究竟是 给她的执迷画上了句点 还是给我的
I couldn't tell whether it was putting an end to her fascination or mine.
全体起立
All rise.
请坐
Be seated.
请起立 史考特女士
Stand up, Ms. Scott.
你被控在2015年8月14日
You are charged with the harassment of Mr. Donald Dunn
至2017年3月22日期间 骚扰唐纳德·邓恩先生
between the dates of 14th August 2015 and 22nd March 2017.
你是否认罪?
Are you guilty or not guilty?
我认罪
Guilty.
你被控在2015年8月14日
You are charged with the stalking of Mr. Donald Dunn
至2017年3月22日期间 跟踪唐纳德·邓恩先生
between the dates of 14th August 2015 and 22nd March 2017.
你是否认罪?
Are you guilty or not guilty?
我认罪
Guilty.
你被控在2016年6月6日 至2017年3月22日期间
You are charged with the harassment of Gerald Dunn and Eleanor Dunn
骚扰杰瑞德·邓恩先生 和艾莉诺·邓恩女士
between the dates of 6th June 2016 and 22nd March 2017.
你是否认罪?
Are you guilty or not guilty?
我认罪
Guilty.
我的小驯鹿
My little reindeer.
史考特女士 你已承认有罪
Ms. Scott, you have pled guilty.
我会请皇家检控署 拟好判决前的调查报告
I will ask the CPS to prepare a pre-sentencing report.
- 在那之前 你将受到拘留 - 小驯鹿
- You will remain in custody until then. - Reindeer.
全体起立
All rise.
小驯鹿
Reindeer.
玛莎被判处九个月监禁
Martha was sentenced to nine months in prison,
与此同时 法院对她下达了为期五年的限制令
and a five-year restraining order was issued that same day.
那天在法庭上 是我最后一次见到她
And there, in that courtroom, was the last time I ever set eyes on her.
警方事件时间表
我为她感到难过 那是我第一眼的直觉
琪莉
Keeley.
你好
Hi.
弗兰西斯给我打了电话
Francis called.
他很担心你
He's concerned about you.
他说你已经窝在房里好几个星期了
He says you've barely come out of your room in weeks.
想进来说吗?
Do you wanna come in?
好啊
Yeah.
这些是什么?
What's all this?
是关于玛莎的信息
Oh, it's, uh... It's Martha stuff.
- 她不是已经被判刑了吗?  - 判了 但我想理清楚整件事
- I thought she'd been sentenced. - She has. I'm trying to make sense of it.
- 进展如何?  - 就快有答案了
- And how's that going?  - I'm getting closer.
我开始对着玛莎的照片手淫
切掉他的阴茎或者割了他的舌头
但愿如此 这一切看起来太疯狂了
Yeah, you'd hope so, looking at all this.
是啊 很疯狂
Yeah, it's crazy.
我还保留着当初为了举报她 而下载的所有语音留言
I have all her voicemails from when I downloaded them for the police.
把它们按她的情绪分类 归进了不同的文件夹
I've split them into all these folders capturing her different emotions.
这几周我都在干这个 但还有一大堆没来得及听
I've been doing it for weeks. There's a ton I haven't listened to yet.
有趣的是 像这样把一切铺开来看
It's funny, 'cause when you see them all splayed out like this,
确实能感受到她有多疯魔
you really do get a sense of just how mad she was.
你想坐会儿吗?
Do you wanna sit down or something?
好啊
Yeah.
你看起来很糟糕
You look awful.
我感觉好极了
I feel awesome.
喜剧事业进展如何?
How's the, uh, comedy going?
我已经放弃了
I've given up.
得到了想要的一切 才发现原来那些根本不适合我
Nothing like getting everything you want in life to realize it's not for you.
话说
So, um,
你为什么来找我?
why are you here?
我想请你搬回我妈的房子 整理一下心情
I want you to move back to my mum's place. Sort yourself out a bit.
不行 我在这里签了租约的
I can't. I've signed a lease here.
别担心 我会替你赔钱
Nah, I'll pay for it.
搬回去吧
Just move back.
我不能眼看你继续过这样的日子
I can't have you go on living like this.
你已经经历了那么多
Having gone through all of that.
唐尼 那个视频真的让我很生气
That video, Donny, it really upset me.
好吧
Okay.
感觉如何?
How does it feel?
嗯 熟悉的感觉
Yeah, familiar.
那我就不打扰了 有什么需要尽管提
I'll leave you to it. Let me know if you need anything.
谢谢
Thank you.
对了 我在壁橱里 给你准备了一份小礼物
I forgot to say, I left a little something for you in the cupboard,
还有一些之前整理出来的小物件
along with a couple of bits and bobs I found.
好的 谢谢
Oh, thanks.
《刽子手哈利》 作者:唐尼·邓恩
这份草稿太棒了 你很有前途
你好
Hello.
有什么需要我帮忙吗?
Can I help with anything?
对 我在想...
Yeah, I was, uh...
我能不能进去说?
I was wondering if I could come in.
当然
Sure.
想喝杯茶吗?
Would you like a cup of tea?
好啊 劳驾
Yeah, please.
所以他们总是一副嗑嗨的样子?
So they were just high all the time?
天哪 我从来没见过 像他俩那样嗑药的人
Oh my God, I've never seen two people consume drugs like them.
而且还都是私立学校的男生
Private school boys too.
我回家时经常发现 有人在我床上乱搞 太离谱了
I mean, the amount of times I caught people shagging in my bed was insane.
你这段时间去哪了?
Where've you been?
就是到处转转
You know. Here and there.
对不起 我忽然玩失踪
I'm sorry I disappeared.
没关系 我能理解
No. No, I get it.
对了 我看了你的视频
I saw your video, by the way.
是吗?
Oh yeah?
我觉得你很勇敢
I thought it was brave.
非常勇敢
Really brave.
谢谢
Thank you.
你应该回来和我一起工作
You should come back and work with me.
不会再像上次那样了
It won't be like last time.
我不知道 我已经没怎么写东西了
Oh, I... I don't know. I'm sort of not really doing much anymore.
我们正准备翻拍《绵口蛇》
We're bringing Cotton Mouth back for a reboot.
也许现在提这个时机很糟
Probably be terrible, but
但我们正在组建拍摄团队
we're staffing up at this very moment.
你会有薪水
You'd be paid.
我很乐意参与
I'd love that.
玛莎的语音留言
恭维话
天哪 还有一次在酒吧里
God, and there was this other time in the bar
你穿着白色的紧身内裤在工作 我当时就想
when you were serving in your tight whites, and I thought,
"红色 红色才适合你"
"Red. Red is your color."
然后第二天 你就穿了红色的
And then the next day, you were wearing red.
我觉得你的下颌线很好看 笑起来特别可爱
I think you've got a great jawline, a lovely smile.
就是...我觉得你很有魅力
You know, I think you're, you know, very attractive.
有时候 当你遇到某个人
You know, when you meet someone sometimes,
你会觉得他就是那个对的人
you just think they have it.
而你也对他一见钟情
And you have it.
我不知道 也许是因为喜欢你的说话方式吧
I dunno. Maybe it's your turn of phrase.
好吧 我喜欢你 行了吧? 我喜欢你 好吧 我说出来了
Fine! I fancy you, okay? I fancy you. There, I said it.
天哪 我脸红得 像个十几岁的处女一样
Oh God. I'm blushing like a teenage virgin here.
你好 请给我一杯伏特加可乐
Hi there. - Hi. Yeah, I'll have a vodka Coke, please.
双倍伏特加 谢谢
A... a double. Thanks.
没听过的
有件事我一直很好奇
That's the thing I've always wondered.
人们为何会相遇和相爱 诸如此类
Why people meet, why people fall in love, that kind of thing.
也许正因如此 我才会把你当成驯鹿宝贝吧
And I suppose that brings me to the baby reindeer thing.
我想你或许也很疑惑
As I think you're probably wondering.
小时候 我有一个可爱的小毛绒玩具
Basically, I had this wee cuddly toy when I was young.
我去哪儿都带着它
Went with me everywhere.
印象中 最早是从圣诞节开始的
Earliest memory I have, I think, was Christmastime.
有一张我的老照片 我坐在那里 头上戴着纸帽子
This old photo of me, sitting with this paper hat on my head
旁边放着一个驯鹿宝贝
and this baby reindeer beside me.
总之 这只小驯鹿毛茸茸的 超级可爱
Anyway, this reindeer was this cuddly, fluffy thing.
它有厚厚的嘴唇 大大的眼睛
It had big lips, huge eyes,
还有最可爱的小屁股
and the cutest wee bum.
我一直保存到现在呢
I still have it to this day.
它是我整个童年唯一的美好了
It was the only good thing about my childhood.
爸妈吵架的时候
I'd hug it
我就会抱着它
when they fought.
他们经常吵架 知道吗?
And they fought a lot, you know?
你长得就像那只小驯鹿一样
Well, you are the spit of that reindeer.
一样的鼻子
The same nose.
一样的眼睛
Same eyes.
一样可爱的小屁股
Same cute wee bum.
它对我来说太重要了
It means so much to me.
你...
You...
你对我来说太重要了
You mean so much to me.
我得先挂了
I've gotta go.
你没事吧?
Are you okay?
没事 抱歉 对 我没事 对不起
Yeah. Yeah. Sorry. Yeah, I'm fine. Sorry.
给
Here you go.
谢谢
Oh, thank you.
- 7块2毛5英镑 - 噢 好的
- It's, uh, £7.25. - Oh yeah.
见鬼
Oh fuck.
抱歉 伙计 我好像把钱包落在家里了
Sorry, man, I...I think I've left my wallet at home.
没关系 算我请你的
Don't worry about it. It's on me.
若你或你认识的人正在经历挣扎
请访问以下网站 寻求相关信息和资源
根据理查德·加德的话剧 《驯鹿宝贝》改编